

PROFILE

Certified Professional in Human Resources (PGDHRM) with extensive background in HR, distinguished by commended performance and proven results. Experience in employee recruitment and retention, staff development, motivation, payroll management, benefits and compensation, HR records management, HR policies development & Planning & Budgeting.

Demonstrated success developing teambuilding programs, corporate policies, job descriptions and management reports.

CONTACT

ADDRESS: 38/A, West Tejturi Bazar,

Farmgate, Dhaka 1215. **PHONE:** 01759 197703

EMAIL: Linnetnusrat7@gmail.com

HR SKILLS

- Recruitment & Retention
- Performance Management
- Expatriate
 Recruitment/Management
- HR Policy Execution
- Payroll Management
- Organizational Development
- Planning & Budgeting
- Employee Relations & Engagement
- Compensation & Benefit
- Employee Counseling
- General Administration

NUSRAT SHARMIN MOURI

HR PROFESSIONAL

WORK EXPERIENCE

SINDABAD.COM LTD. Assistant Manager – HR Operations (2018 – Till Date)



- Prepare manning budget according to the organization demand and ensure recruitment process as per company rules.
- Responsible for preparing, entering and monitoring department budget.
- Maintain effective HRIS to keep confidential employee & Mgt. information.
- Prepare employee related letters, employee database management, exit management and other HR Operations activities
- Ensure the implementation of standard performance appraisal system to measure employee's performance monthly basis.
- Handle the grievance and disciplinary issues smoothly and ensure proper discipline in the organization.
- Assist in training & awareness building workshop with employees & staffs for workplace safety and Environmental conservation and safe chemical handling.
- Ensure management system of Health, Safety & Environment conforms to the requirements of national & International Standard.
- Handling Expatriate recruitment process.

Sr. Executive - HR & Admin (2017 – 2018) Executive - HR & Admin (2016 – 2017)

Achievements:

- Revised job descriptions across all levels and 15+ categories and organograms of all departments.
- Successfully handled 13 Expatriates recruitment process & visa & work permit related activities.
- Designed all letter / Certificate formats for the organization.
- Streamlined the procedures and policies.
- Worked on establishing the company culture according to company values.

TRAININGS

- Undergone 3 months training on
- "Graphics & Web UI design" from BASIS Institute of Technology & Management (BITM).
- Undergone 6 months training on "MS Office and Graphics Design" from Bhuiyan Computers Limited.
- Undergone month long training on
- "Advanced HR & Administration Management Powered by Excel" conducted by Bdjobs.com.
- Undergone day long workshop on
- "Corporate Grooming & Etiquette" conducted by Solaiman Shukhon.

CERTIFICATE COURSE

ACMP 4.0 at **IBA/DU** in collaboration with IIT -Delhi & IIM - Ahmedabad with support from ICT Division, BCC, LICT, Digital Bangladesh & LeadSoft.

AFFILIATION

Active general member of **BIM Alumni Association (BIMAA).**

COMPUTER SKILLS

- MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook)
- Graphics Design

HOBBIES

- Reading novels
- Watching movies
- Listening music
- Fabrication work

- Designed and implemented Quarterly Performance Management System for the organization.
- Prepared HR Departments all SOPs.
- Successfully completed "Robi Distribution project" which includes 11
 Distribution House setup, 270+ DSR/DS recruitment, and payroll
 processing within less than 1 month time period.

THE DNS GROUP INC. Executive – HR & Admin (2015 – 2016)



- Handling Office Staff / Workers Database (File Management), Leaves and Attendance Management.
- Supporting the recruitment & selection process.
- Producing documents, briefing papers, reports and presentation
- Conducting employee orientation.
- Responsible Transport Maintenance and other activities related to this
- Maintaining Personal/Business files.
- To carry out any activity given by CEO.

CHARTERED UNIVERSITY COLLEGE Assistant Course Coordinator (2012 – 2015)



- Coordinate and guide teachers.
- Solve and counsel academic and administrative problems of teachers, students, Parents as and when required.
- Exam invigilation and controller of CBE Exam.
- Online Registration of FD / ACCA and providing other registration related services for students.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION

Post Graduate Diploma in Human Resource Management (PGDHRM)

Bangladesh Institute of Management (2016 - 2017)

CGPA: 3.85 on a 4.00 scale

Master's in Business Administration (MBA)

State University of Bangladesh (2015 - 2016)

CGPA: 3.92 on a 4.00 scale

Master of Arts in English

National University (Eden Mohila College) (2011 - 2012)

CGPA / Class: 2nd Class

Bachelor of Arts in English

National University (Eden Mohila College) (2006 - 2010)

CGPA / Class: 2nd Class

Higher Secondary School Certificate

Shaheed Bir Uttam Lt. Anwar Girls' School & College (2004 - 2005) CGPA: 4.30

Secondary School Certificate

Vidyamoyee Govt. Girls' High School, Mymensingh (2002 - 2003) CGPA: 4.50